<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>TextMining on Log Blog</title>
    <link>https://alanoakes.github.io/tags/textmining/</link>
    <description>Recent content in TextMining on Log Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2023 00:43:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alanoakes.github.io/tags/textmining/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Word Study In The Terminal</title>
      <link>https://alanoakes.github.io/bible-miner-bash-forgiveness/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2023 00:43:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alanoakes.github.io/bible-miner-bash-forgiveness/</guid>
      <description>Overview In my nerdy bible study tonight (shown in the picture below), I found something so profound, amazing and simple&amp;hellip;
I was looking for the most common word usage of forgiveness throughout the Bible and its this Hebrew word [ נָשָׂא - nāśā&#39;] with the Strongs number H5375, and it shows up all throughout the Bible!
Example Uses The word picture is so powerful as shown in its top 10 uses:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Excel String Cleaner Add-In</title>
      <link>https://alanoakes.github.io/vba-string-cleaner-addin/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jul 2023 23:58:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alanoakes.github.io/vba-string-cleaner-addin/</guid>
      <description>Here is a free Excel Add-In to clean dirty text the easy way!
Back Story I have had to make several text cleaning functionalities for the front-end of Excel lately due banking entries, randomized strings, you name it.
I thought, why not just build an Add-In I can install in any workbook that needs it? Also, I figured you guys could use it since there doesn’t seem to be any Excel function like this.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Word Study Sankey Chart</title>
      <link>https://alanoakes.github.io/bible-miner-sankey-chart/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jul 2023 13:23:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alanoakes.github.io/bible-miner-sankey-chart/</guid>
      <description>Overview I am currently taking a break from the high computing power of R libraries and learning how these these tools can practically work in other applications.
One such chart is the Sankey Chart. I decided to make one using Visual Basic for my bible word study.
Sankey charts really help do bible word studies (i.e. text mining) since it helps see what counting word usage (translations) alone cannot.
Example Word Study For example, each biblical use of the word &amp;ldquo;jealous&amp;rdquo; is important in its own way.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
